## CAREER PROFILE

Sr. IT admin for the startup Anaconda Inc as employee #9 that has now expanded to over 150. Initially, I was a utility IT admin responsible for diverse operations such as for INFOSEC, Cloud services, Infrastructure and planning, product and company documentation, customer support, product testing, graphics design, and general employee and customer support. As the company increased in size, I helped to organize various departments to offload the diverse projects and am now primarily focused on Business IT and data security. Prior to Anaconda Inc, I worked for Enthought Scientific Computing Solutions for 4 years doing software testing and IT Administration.

## **EXPERIENCES**

#### Sr. IT Systems Administartor

Anaconda Inc, Austin TX

Accomplishments

- Managed and maintained complex software development and business operations infrastructure
- Development of development, test, acceptance, production, both on-premises and AWS cloud-based environments
- Internal business operations for accounting, HR, marketing, sales, and customer support
- Performed continuous builds of 100+ servers running: Redhat, Debian, Windows, and OSX systems using Salt, Puppet and Ansible
- · Automated deployment saving time and money
- Developed and standardized software test harness to improve product quality and eliminate manual development activities to increase developer production time
- Wrote technical documentation and standard operating procedures for software product as well as company policies and employee documentation
- · Early employee, developed and implemented IT Infrastructure
- IT department manager reporting to Director of IT

#### Primary Responsibilities

 Maintain Security, Network Infrastructure, Virtualization, Cloud Services, Developer and User Requests

#### Tech Skills

- Online Service: AWS, Azure, DigitalOcean, DockerHub, Circle CI, TravisCI, Appveyor
- Software: VMWare, Hypervisor, Windows, OS X, Linux, VirtualBox, Docker, Vagrant, Puppet, Salt, Ansible, Django, OpenStack, Network IOS, Cisco KVM, JAMF, Windows Server, Jenkins, Django, Wordpress, Crashplan, Duo, Cisco AMP and Firesight, ELK Stack, Nginx, Apache, LDAP
- Hardware: Cisco, Dell, HP, Apple, PC
- Languages: Unix, Python, HTML, CSS, some PHP, C, SQL

#### IT Systems Administrator

2010 - 2012

2012 - 2017

Enthought Inc, Austin TX

Managed and Maintained Enthought's network IT infrastructure. Setup and managed LDAP database. Desktop support for the Austin office. Assist in conference and event preparations. Audio visual and graphic design projects. Software testing and documentation.

#### **Customer Support Engineer**

KLA-Tencor, Austin TX

2010 - 2012

Hardware and software systems analyst providing service for semiconductor manufacturing equipment in a clean-room environment, requiring outstanding troubleshooting and problem-solving ability. Act as the first line of communication with clients representing the company with excellent interpersonal customer service skills. Work with a support team of customers, managers, and other technicians, especially on complicated projects, yet function autonomously requiring high organizational skills and a self-motivated attitude.

# SKILLS & PROFICIENCY





## **Troy Powell**

Sr Sys Admin / DevOps Engineer

**(**512)757-6356

🔇 www.troypowell.info

in troypowell28

( ) tpowellcio

🔰 @thepalsrus

#### **EDUCATION**

AWS Certification
Udemny
2017~

BS in Information Technology University of Phoer

University of Phoenix 2007

AAS in Electronic Engineering Technology Brigham Young University Idaho 1998

#### **LANGUAGES**

English (Native)

Bash

Python

### INTERESTS

Family

Learning

Diet/Exercise

Woodworking

Fishing

Boardgames